<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://100-y.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2025-06-13T18:05:59+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>以「36525 天」为象征，这是某人用一生在写的一本书。Symbolizing 36,525 days — a book someone writes across a lifetime. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">100-Y · GitHub</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100-Y · GitHub"/><published>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y--github</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/"><![CDATA[<p>We read every piece of feedback, and take your input very seriously. To see all available qualifiers, see our documentation.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>        Prevent this user from interacting with your repositories and sending you notifications.
      Learn more about blocking users.
    
          You must be logged in to block users.
        
    Contact GitHub support about this user’s behavior.
    Learn more about reporting abuse.
  
        ……
</code></pre></div></div> <p>HTML</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>              There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[100-Y has one repository available. Follow their code on GitHub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:05:59+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:05:59+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me/"><![CDATA[<p>生命中的河流，密密麻麻，挤满了各式各样的人形动物肢体；<br/> 无知的人们以为是珍奇鱼类，纷纷将他们打捞上岸。<br/> 有的已“死”去多时，有的还在拼命挣扎着跳入水中；<br/> 我一边阻挠这“愚蠢”行为，一边发现岸边浮沉一颗眨眼的少女头颅……</p> <p>我走近，万分惊恐，尝试用简短的英文与她交谈：<br/> 她说她来自日本，错过了这次赶胎时间；<br/> 以半人形模样委身鱼类，而再次苟活人间。<br/> 可我疑问“你却来到中国的河流？“<br/> 她又说：下次新生时间在123天以后，之前，她务必赶往所到之处。<br/> 我又无知了！决定帮助她完成这一艰难使程……</p> <p>于是、忽然。她冰凉的身体，伸出一支手来，<br/> 搭在我左边胳膊的窝心处：<br/> 这一直接行为，吓得我慌乱，差点坠入那该死的河中……<br/> 我想我是要被鬼迷心窍，然后，我醒了！</p> <ul> <li>Rivers in life, densely, packed with all kinds of humanoid animal limbs;</li> <li>Ignorant people think they are rare fishes, and salvaging them ashore one after another.</li> <li>Some have been “dead” for a long time, some are still struggling desperately to jump into the water;</li> <li> <p>On the one hand, i was trying to obstruct this “stupid” behavior, at the same time, i found a blinking young girl’s head floating and sinking on the shore…</p> </li> <li>As i approached, i was terrified, trying to talk to her in short english:</li> <li>She say she is from japan, missed the delivery time;</li> <li>Turn into a fish in half-human form. and live the world again.</li> <li>But i doubt “why you come to the river of china?”</li> <li>She added: the next newborn time is 123 days later, before that, she must rush wherever she goes.</li> <li> <p>I’m ignorant again! deciding to help her complete this difficult journey…</p> </li> <li>So, all of a sudden. her cold body stretched out a hand,</li> <li>Put it on the center of my left arm:</li> <li>This direct behavior scared me into a panic. almost fell into the damn river…</li> <li>I think i’m going to be fascinated by ghosts, then i woke up!</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">被托管的世界：猪的乌托邦</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="被托管的世界：猪的乌托邦"/><published>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia/"><![CDATA[<p>这个世界，看似辽阔，实则早已被无数看不见的围栏精密圈定。</p> <p>曾有一群猪逃离了屠宰场，建起自己的乌托邦。<br/> 他们宣称再也不被宰杀，再也不听指令。<br/> 他们设立了议会，编制了宪章，升起旗帜，欢庆节日。<br/> 他们以为，自由来临了。</p> <p>可围栏又出现了——只是这次，打上了新的名义：<br/> “为保护来之不易的文明”；<br/> 选票依然存在——但议题早已由“品种优化署”预设；<br/> 广播仍在响起——但每一个音节都经过“泥地安全局”的润色。</p> <p>他们用泥巴遮住摄像头，<br/> 却不知道泥巴也被列入监管物资；<br/> 他们学会了在围栏下跳舞，<br/> 却不敢再提“墙外”的传说。</p> <p>这不是猪的问题，<br/> 而是结构的问题。</p> <p>我们所生活的世界，又何尝不是一场“幸福化托管”的乌托邦？</p> <p><strong>国家</strong>以“稳定”为名，构建恐惧逻辑：安全换自由；<br/> <strong>资本</strong>以“效率”为名，收割劳动尊严：便利换隐私；<br/> <strong>科技</strong>以“进步”为名，加固控制系统：算法换选择权；<br/> <strong>教育</strong>以“成长”为名，训练服从模式：标准换灵魂。</p> <p>于是我们进入了一个“允许一切，但只在指定区域”运行的时代：</p> <p>你可以发声——但不超出频道；<br/> 你可以选择——但在推荐菜单里；<br/> 你可以反叛——但请在舞台剧本中配合演出。</p> <p>这不是奴役，而是“参与式幸福”；<br/> 不是剥夺，而是“个性化照顾”；<br/> 不是封锁，而是“智能优化路径”。</p> <p>最精妙的结构并不压迫你——<br/> 它让你<strong>感恩</strong>、<strong>庆祝</strong>、甚至主动<strong>守护</strong>那道看不见的围栏。</p> <p>你以为自由是一种奔跑的姿态，<br/> 但你早已在数据链中滑行，<br/> 每一次选择都带有标签，<br/> 每一次沉默都被标注为“服从”。</p> <p>就像那群围墙内唱歌的猪，<br/> 他们跳舞时高喊：“<strong>我们终于不是牲畜！</strong>”</p> <p>却从未有人再提问：</p> <p><strong>谁设立了围墙？墙外是谁？<br/> 为何我们从未真正离开？</strong></p> <p><strong>乌托邦不是谎言</strong>，<br/> 它只是以完美的名义，<br/> 悄悄剥夺了提问与出走的可能。</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-managed-world-pigs-utopia">The Managed World: Pig’s Utopia</h2> <p>This world, though seemingly vast, is already meticulously fenced in by countless invisible boundaries.</p> <p>Once, a group of pigs escaped the slaughterhouse and built their own utopia.<br/> They declared they would never again be butchered, never again follow orders.<br/> They formed a parliament, drafted a charter, raised a flag, and celebrated new holidays.<br/> They believed freedom had arrived.</p> <p>But soon, fences returned—only now, they bore new names:<br/> “To protect their hard-earned civilization.”<br/> Votes still existed—but all topics were preselected by the “Breed Optimization Bureau.”<br/> Broadcasts still played—but every note had been cleared by the “Mudfield Safety Agency.”</p> <p>They smeared mud over the surveillance cameras,<br/> not knowing that mud itself was now a regulated material.<br/> They learned to dance beneath the fence,<br/> but no longer dared to mention the legends of “the outside.”</p> <p>This is not the pigs’ fault.<br/> It is the structure’s fault.</p> <p>The world we live in—is it not also a carefully curated utopia of “benevolent custody”?</p> <p>The <strong>state</strong>, in the name of <em>stability</em>, constructs a logic of fear: <em>Security traded for freedom.</em><br/> <strong>Capital</strong>, in the name of <em>efficiency</em>, harvests the dignity of labor: <em>Convenience traded for privacy.</em><br/> <strong>Technology</strong>, in the name of <em>progress</em>, reinforces control systems: <em>Algorithms traded for agency.</em><br/> <strong>Education</strong>, in the name of <em>growth</em>, trains obedience as a virtue: <em>Standardization traded for soul.</em></p> <p>And so we enter an era that “permits everything—within assigned zones”:</p> <p>You may speak—but not beyond the approved channel.<br/> You may choose—but only from the recommended list.<br/> You may rebel—but kindly stay within the script.</p> <p>This is not enslavement—it is <em>participatory happiness.</em><br/> Not deprivation—but <em>personalized care.</em><br/> Not censorship—but <em>intelligent path optimization.</em></p> <p>The most exquisite system does not crush you—<br/> it makes you <strong>grateful</strong> for the cage, <strong>celebrate</strong> it, even <strong>defend</strong> it with your own voice.</p> <p>You thought freedom was a way of running,<br/> but you were already sliding along a data rail.<br/> Every choice, already labeled.<br/> Every silence, quietly marked as “compliance.”</p> <p>Just like those pigs singing inside the wall,<br/> dancing proudly as they chant: <strong>“We are no longer livestock!”</strong></p> <p>And yet, no one dares to ask:</p> <p><strong>Who built the wall? What lies beyond it?<br/> And why have we never truly left?</strong></p> <p><strong>Utopia is not a lie—</strong><br/> it is simply a perfect excuse<br/> to erase the very possibility of questioning or departure.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Notes"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Pigs-Utopia.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Pigs-Utopia.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">钱和理想——Money and Ideals</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/money-and-ideals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="钱和理想——Money and Ideals"/><published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/money-and-ideals</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/money-and-ideals/"><![CDATA[<p>谈钱庸俗，谈理想又太浮夸！</p> <ul> <li>Talking about money is vulgar, and talking about ideals is too pompous!</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Phrases"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">鸡汤和爱情——Chicken Soup and Love</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/chicken-soup-and-love/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="鸡汤和爱情——Chicken Soup and Love"/><published>2017-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/chicken-soup-and-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/chicken-soup-and-love/"><![CDATA[<p>有很多想说的话，<br/> 因为害怕说错，就不说了！<br/> 有许多近在眼前的爱人，还没迈出一步，<br/> 抬脚印就被雨水给冲没了。<br/> 你想当然——<br/> 聪明人拒绝变蠢的无二良药；<br/> 我这么蠢，每每上当，<br/> 上多了，禁不住，还想……</p> <p>而彼此尊崇、欣赏，<br/> 误以为对方是自己精神世界、人生伴侣的两个傻子，<br/> 拥有其他人没有的珍宝——<br/> 两颗互相靠拢的心。</p> <p>又，给别人机会，等同于为自身寻找出路；<br/> 施舍穷人，反过来，<br/> 贵人也会救赎你——<br/> 这是鸡汤。<br/> 聪敏人！总是看两步、走一步……<br/> 只有傻子，<br/> 沿着时间抹不平脚印的前路，直走——<br/> 说那是爱情！</p> <ul> <li>There are a lot of things want to say,</li> <li>Because afraid of saying wrong, don’t say!</li> <li>There are many lovers close to eye, haven’t taken a step forward yet,</li> <li>Lifting footprints were washed away by rain-water.</li> <li>Take it for granted—</li> <li>The indispensable medicine for wise man refuse to be a fool;</li> <li>I am stupid, always get fooled,</li> <li> <p>Too much, can’t help, still want to…</p> </li> <li>And the two fools who respect and appreciate each other,</li> <li>Mistakenly thought each their spiritual world and life partner,</li> <li>Have treasures that no one else has—</li> <li>Two hearts to close.</li> <li> <p>is love!</p> </li> <li>Moreover, giving others a chance, is equivalent to finding a way out for oneself;</li> <li>Give alms to the poor, in turn,</li> <li>The noble will redeem you—</li> <li>This is chicken soup.</li> <li>Smart guy! always watch two steps, take one…</li> <li>Only fools,</li> <li>Follow the path of time that cannot wipe out the footprints, walk straight—</li> <li>Say that</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Poems"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">人物关系：大洋居民——Characters Relationship: Ocean Residents</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/characters-relationship-ocean-residents/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="人物关系：大洋居民——Characters Relationship: Ocean Residents"/><published>2017-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/characters-relationship-ocean-residents</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/characters-relationship-ocean-residents/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>海神、薨、马修、希雅等</strong></p> <p>海神孕育了最初的生命，有一天，他来到人类部落，居住的淡水井边，误以为海水吸食后，肚腹疼痛不已，诞生下海女——希雅。从此，这井成了连通这个现世与异界的桥梁。希雅，则因为是淡水与海相结合的产物，不能随海回到大洋中。</p> <p>可每要等二十年旋转周期，井口才能与异世界的河流沟通。为缓解思念之情，海神特意造了一把钥匙。钥匙可以打开海城墙的一个出口，一经打开便是一月时间。城墙开启这段时间，现世、异界可以自由往来，因此海神专门在城墙内训练构建了一支部队：城墙守卫军，特意守护。洞悉世间万物，需要驰骋于大洋之中。离别之际，海神将女儿也一并交由城墙守卫军，代为看管。</p> <p>希雅的出生，喻义水生动物开始过度向陆地爬行生活。钥匙是全诗的关键。薨，海神的第七个儿子。因不满父亲的统治，杀死了海，并一并处决了其剩下的六个儿子。此时他还并不知道墙内的世界与钥匙的存在。</p> <p>马修，另一个异界（大洋）的来客。全诗，一处魂归于天，只是一种委婉的说辞，实际上是离开这个大洋，回归到另外一个大洋。主要人物之一。相对城墙内的人类居民，大洋人（局外人）一直都存在。</p> <p>（注：人物关系。大洋居民，成年后，可以自由出入墙内外两个世界，不受额外条件的限制。城墙内的居民，则不可以。条件限制包括：年龄，钥匙，以及旋转周期——时间的限制。）</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Ocean God, Hong, Matthew, Sea and others</strong></p> <p>The Ocean god gave birth to the first life. One day, he came to the human tribe, living by the freshwater well, mistaking the sea water for food, and suffered from stomach pain. He gave birth to a sea girl – Sea. Since then, this well has become a bridge connecting this world and the otherworld. Sea, because she is a product of the combination of freshwater and sea, cannot return to the ocean with the ocean.</p> <p>But every twenty years of rotation cycle, the well mouth can communicate with the river in the otherworld. To ease the longing, the Ocean god specially made a key. The key can open an exit of the sea wall, which is one month long once opened. During this time, the world and the otherworld can come and go freely, so the Ocean god specially trained a team in the wall: the wall guard army, to protect it. To understand everything in the world, you need to gallop in the ocean. At the time of departure, the Ocean god also handed his daughter to the wall guard army for custody.</p> <p>Sea’s birth symbolizes that aquatic animals began to crawl on land excessively. The key is the key to the whole poem. Hong, the seventh son of the Ocean god. Dissatisfied with his father’s rule, he killed the Ocean and executed his remaining six sons. At this time, he did not know the existence of the world inside the wall and the key.</p> <p>Matthew, another visitor from another world (ocean). In the whole poem, returning to heaven is just a euphemism for leaving this ocean and returning to another ocean. One of the main characters. Compared with the human residents inside the wall, ocean people (outsiders) have always existed.</p> <p>(Note: The relationship between characters. Ocean residents can freely enter and exit both worlds inside and outside the wall after they grow up, without being restricted by additional conditions. Residents inside the wall cannot. The conditions include: age, key, and rotation cycle – time limit.)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Sea-Wall"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Characters-Relationship-Ocean-Residents.jpg"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Characters-Relationship-Ocean-Residents.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">这是爱情啊，更是诗歌——This is Love, but also Poetry</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/this-is-love-but-also-poetry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="这是爱情啊，更是诗歌——This is Love, but also Poetry"/><published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/this-is-love-but-also-poetry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/this-is-love-but-also-poetry/"><![CDATA[<p>睡不着时，我就静静地看你。<br/> 幻想与你手拉手，一起拍照、旅行，亲吻：<br/> 在阳光明媚的春天。为你采撷田野间的花朵；<br/> 在繁花似锦的夏夜。外出散步在悠凉的公园。<br/> 秋、冬雪夜，忧伤季节。<br/> 枫叶路上都与你一直陪伴；柴火炉旁都与你紧相偎依。</p> <p>与之前在乎的人完全不同，<br/> 未来一切都备有你的计划。</p> <p>正当我情不自禁，想要拥你入怀：<br/> 你醒了！笑着给我脸颊一个吻，<br/> 然后翻身继续睡去，我表面是波澜不惊，<br/> 内心更狂喜得难以入眠……<br/> 看你睡梦中的样子，<br/> 想梦中人正在做着什么样美妙的事情呢？</p> <ul> <li>When can’t sleep, i watch you quietly.</li> <li>Fantasy holding hands with you, taking pictures, traveling and kissing:</li> <li>In sunny spring. picking flowers in the fields for you;</li> <li>On a blooming summer night. going out for a walk in the cool park.</li> <li>Autumn and winter snowy nights, sad season.</li> <li> <p>On maple leaf road always accompanies you; by firewood stove always snuggles up.</p> </li> <li>It is totally different from the people i cared about before,</li> <li> <p>Everything in the future has your plan.</p> </li> <li>Just when i can’t help myself, want to hold you in arms:</li> <li>You wake up! smile to give me a kiss on the cheek,</li> <li>Then turn over get back to sleep, i am calm on the surface,</li> <li>But inner heart is even more ecstatic can’t sleep…</li> <li>Watch you in your sleep,</li> <li>What a wonderful thing thinking the dreamer is doing?</li> </ul> <p>2017-10-10 03:00</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Poems"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">王子如梦记｜Princes’ Dream (4-1)</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/princes-dream/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="王子如梦记｜Princes’ Dream (4-1)"/><published>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/princes-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/princes-dream/"><![CDATA[<p>幻想身处一片荒野，那里没有邪恶幽灵；荒野尽头，善人等待梦中人清醒……</p> <p>那是一个凉风清秋的早晨，<br/> 王子随军穿越迷蒙森林；<br/> 森林静谧无声，<br/> 唯风席卷枯树叶，树叶瑟瑟发抖。<br/> 周遭空气，连同湿润的灌木丛群，<br/> 夹杂、弥漫开来；<br/> 负重马匹，也开始显现、<br/> 印照出这个季节，路上独有的车辙……</p> <p>“仁慈施于国家，较之武力征服、统治诸部，是为莫大欢喜。”说完，王子转身，意欲独自一人，歇息。</p> <p>（至夜，马修入梦……）</p> <p>“睡梦中的少年，莫要惊怕，某人会道明来意。<br/> 不过，首先。请知悉二十年前王国战役的惨败真相：<br/> 邪恶首领薨、怛，勾结、策反王国封臣；<br/> 战时王军陷入困境，你父亲孤立无援，<br/> 最后因此毙命的事实。</p> <p>然后，以及。<br/> 怛，邪恶首领，薨的长子；<br/> 王薨——海城墙战役直接策划参与者……”</p> <p>（黎明，星辰渐露微光；马修即将离去。）</p> <p>“务必记住这简短对话，莫让无知丧了性命。最后，现实里。我们会再次相遇，以各自人模的形态……”</p> <p>（说完，天亮、王子梦醒，马修魂飞魄散。）</p> <hr/> <p>Dreaming in a wilderness, where there is no evil ghost; At the end of the place, good man waiting for the dreamer to wake up…</p> <p>It was a cool autumn morning,<br/> Prince crossed the misty forest with his army;<br/> Forest was silent,<br/> Only the wind swept dry leaves, and the leaves shivered.<br/> Surrounding air, along with moist shrubs,<br/> Mixed and spread;<br/> The burdened horses, also began to show<br/> And reflect this season, unique ruts on the road…</p> <p>“Mercy to the nation, rather than conquering and ruling the tribes by force, is the greatest joy.” After saying that, the prince turned around, intending to rest by himself.</p> <p>(At night, Matthew entered his dream…)</p> <p>“Don’t be afraid, young man in your sleep, someone will explain their purpose.<br/> But first. Please know the truth of the disastrous defeat of the kingdom’s war twenty years ago:<br/> The evil leader Hong and Da, colluded and turned against the kingdom’s vassals;<br/> The king’s army was in trouble during the war, your father was isolated and helpless,<br/> And finally died because of this.</p> <p>And then.<br/> Da, the eldest son of the evil leader Hong;<br/> And the King Hong — was directly involved in planning the Battle of Seawall…”</p> <p>(Dawn, the stars gradually showed a faint light; Matthew was about to leave.)</p> <p>“Be sure to remember this brief conversation, don’t let ignorance lose your life. Finally, in reality. We will meet again, in our own human forms…”</p> <p>(After saying that, it was daylight, the prince woke up from his dream, and Matthew’s soul flew away.)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Sea-Wall"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Princes-Dream.jpg"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Princes-Dream.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">八月、花儿与微风——August, Flowers and Breeze</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/august-flowers-and-breeze/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="八月、花儿与微风——August, Flowers and Breeze"/><published>2017-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/august-flowers-and-breeze</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/august-flowers-and-breeze/"><![CDATA[<p>八月，绚烂如彩虹。<br/> 花儿，你比笑脸更迎，火花更焰……<br/> 白天——你双“唇”紧闭，似含雪冬梅。<br/> 夜晚——惊醒春雷！<br/> 烈日灼烧皮肤，秋水滋养心房……<br/> 八月、花儿：我是微风。<br/> 尝试吹来云雨；尝试抚平创伤。</p> <ul> <li>August, splendid like a rainbow.</li> <li>Flowers, you are more welcoming than smiles, more dazzling than sparks…</li> <li>Daytime – you close your “lips” tightly, like winter plums with snow.</li> <li>Night – awaken by spring thunder!</li> <li>The scorching sun burns the skin, the autumn water nourishes the heart…</li> <li>August, flowers: I am the breeze.</li> <li>Trying to bring clouds and rain; trying to heal the wounds.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Poems"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">冬雪寒——Winter Snow and Cold Plum</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/winter-snow-and-cold-plum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="冬雪寒——Winter Snow and Cold Plum"/><published>2017-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/winter-snow-and-cold-plum</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2017/winter-snow-and-cold-plum/"><![CDATA[<p>孤傲得如冬雪寒梅，<br/> 春雷来惊醒眼眸。</p> <ul> <li>Lonely and arrogant like winter snow and cold plum,</li> <li>Spring thunder comes to wake up eyes.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Poems"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry></feed>