<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://100-y.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2025-06-13T17:57:11+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>以「36525 天」为象征，这是某人用一生在写的一本书。Symbolizing 36,525 days — a book someone writes across a lifetime. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">100-Y · GitHub</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100-Y · GitHub"/><published>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y--github</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/"><![CDATA[<p>We read every piece of feedback, and take your input very seriously. To see all available qualifiers, see our documentation.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>        Prevent this user from interacting with your repositories and sending you notifications.
      Learn more about blocking users.
    
          You must be logged in to block users.
        
    Contact GitHub support about this user’s behavior.
    Learn more about reporting abuse.
  
        ……
</code></pre></div></div> <p>HTML</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>              There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[100-Y has one repository available. Follow their code on GitHub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">被托管的世界：猪的乌托邦</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="被托管的世界：猪的乌托邦"/><published>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/pigs-utopia/"><![CDATA[<p>这个世界，看似辽阔，实则早已被无数看不见的围栏精密圈定。</p> <p>曾有一群猪逃离了屠宰场，建起自己的乌托邦。<br/> 他们宣称再也不被宰杀，再也不听指令。<br/> 他们设立了议会，编制了宪章，升起旗帜，欢庆节日。<br/> 他们以为，自由来临了。</p> <p>可围栏又出现了——只是这次，打上了新的名义：<br/> “为保护来之不易的文明”；<br/> 选票依然存在——但议题早已由“品种优化署”预设；<br/> 广播仍在响起——但每一个音节都经过“泥地安全局”的润色。</p> <p>他们用泥巴遮住摄像头，<br/> 却不知道泥巴也被列入监管物资；<br/> 他们学会了在围栏下跳舞，<br/> 却不敢再提“墙外”的传说。</p> <p>这不是猪的问题，<br/> 而是结构的问题。</p> <p>我们所生活的世界，又何尝不是一场“幸福化托管”的乌托邦？</p> <p><strong>国家</strong>以“稳定”为名，构建恐惧逻辑：安全换自由；<br/> <strong>资本</strong>以“效率”为名，收割劳动尊严：便利换隐私；<br/> <strong>科技</strong>以“进步”为名，加固控制系统：算法换选择权；<br/> <strong>教育</strong>以“成长”为名，训练服从模式：标准换灵魂。</p> <p>于是我们进入了一个“允许一切，但只在指定区域”运行的时代：</p> <p>你可以发声——但不超出频道；<br/> 你可以选择——但在推荐菜单里；<br/> 你可以反叛——但请在舞台剧本中配合演出。</p> <p>这不是奴役，而是“参与式幸福”；<br/> 不是剥夺，而是“个性化照顾”；<br/> 不是封锁，而是“智能优化路径”。</p> <p>最精妙的结构并不压迫你——<br/> 它让你<strong>感恩</strong>、<strong>庆祝</strong>、甚至主动<strong>守护</strong>那道看不见的围栏。</p> <p>你以为自由是一种奔跑的姿态，<br/> 但你早已在数据链中滑行，<br/> 每一次选择都带有标签，<br/> 每一次沉默都被标注为“服从”。</p> <p>就像那群围墙内唱歌的猪，<br/> 他们跳舞时高喊：“<strong>我们终于不是牲畜！</strong>”</p> <p>却从未有人再提问：</p> <p><strong>谁设立了围墙？墙外是谁？<br/> 为何我们从未真正离开？</strong></p> <p><strong>乌托邦不是谎言</strong>，<br/> 它只是以完美的名义，<br/> 悄悄剥夺了提问与出走的可能。</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-managed-world-pigs-utopia">The Managed World: Pig’s Utopia</h2> <p>This world, though seemingly vast, is already meticulously fenced in by countless invisible boundaries.</p> <p>Once, a group of pigs escaped the slaughterhouse and built their own utopia.<br/> They declared they would never again be butchered, never again follow orders.<br/> They formed a parliament, drafted a charter, raised a flag, and celebrated new holidays.<br/> They believed freedom had arrived.</p> <p>But soon, fences returned—only now, they bore new names:<br/> “To protect their hard-earned civilization.”<br/> Votes still existed—but all topics were preselected by the “Breed Optimization Bureau.”<br/> Broadcasts still played—but every note had been cleared by the “Mudfield Safety Agency.”</p> <p>They smeared mud over the surveillance cameras,<br/> not knowing that mud itself was now a regulated material.<br/> They learned to dance beneath the fence,<br/> but no longer dared to mention the legends of “the outside.”</p> <p>This is not the pigs’ fault.<br/> It is the structure’s fault.</p> <p>The world we live in—is it not also a carefully curated utopia of “benevolent custody”?</p> <p>The <strong>state</strong>, in the name of <em>stability</em>, constructs a logic of fear: <em>Security traded for freedom.</em><br/> <strong>Capital</strong>, in the name of <em>efficiency</em>, harvests the dignity of labor: <em>Convenience traded for privacy.</em><br/> <strong>Technology</strong>, in the name of <em>progress</em>, reinforces control systems: <em>Algorithms traded for agency.</em><br/> <strong>Education</strong>, in the name of <em>growth</em>, trains obedience as a virtue: <em>Standardization traded for soul.</em></p> <p>And so we enter an era that “permits everything—within assigned zones”:</p> <p>You may speak—but not beyond the approved channel.<br/> You may choose—but only from the recommended list.<br/> You may rebel—but kindly stay within the script.</p> <p>This is not enslavement—it is <em>participatory happiness.</em><br/> Not deprivation—but <em>personalized care.</em><br/> Not censorship—but <em>intelligent path optimization.</em></p> <p>The most exquisite system does not crush you—<br/> it makes you <strong>grateful</strong> for the cage, <strong>celebrate</strong> it, even <strong>defend</strong> it with your own voice.</p> <p>You thought freedom was a way of running,<br/> but you were already sliding along a data rail.<br/> Every choice, already labeled.<br/> Every silence, quietly marked as “compliance.”</p> <p>Just like those pigs singing inside the wall,<br/> dancing proudly as they chant: <strong>“We are no longer livestock!”</strong></p> <p>And yet, no one dares to ask:</p> <p><strong>Who built the wall? What lies beyond it?<br/> And why have we never truly left?</strong></p> <p><strong>Utopia is not a lie—</strong><br/> it is simply a perfect excuse<br/> to erase the very possibility of questioning or departure.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Notes"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Pigs-Utopia.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/Pigs-Utopia.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">凡星——Ordinary Stars</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2010/ordinary-stars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="凡星——Ordinary Stars"/><published>2010-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2010/ordinary-stars</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2010/ordinary-stars/"><![CDATA[<p>我能够企及的只有，<br/> 眼前的那几颗凡星；<br/> 是渴望跃动着的，<br/> 灯、火。<br/> 那遥远模糊视线的东西，<br/> 根本没有必要望见。</p> <ul> <li>I can reach only few,</li> <li>Ordinary stars in front of me;</li> <li>It is the lamp, the fire,</li> <li>Longs to dance.</li> <li>Thing that far-off blurred vision,</li> <li>There is no need to see it at all.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Poems"/><category term="tag1"/><category term="tag2"/><category term="tag3"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[完整描述，用于搜索引擎与社交平台预览，最长 160 字，可与 excerpt 一致]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://100-y.github.io/media/your-image.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry></feed>