<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://36525.day/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://36525.day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>以「36525 天」为象征，这是某人用一生在写的一本书 / Symbolizing 36,525 days — a book someone writes across a lifetime </subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-10-13-characters-relationship-ocean-residents/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-10-13-characters-relationship-ocean-residents</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-10-13-characters-relationship-ocean-residents/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p><strong>海神、薨、马修、希雅等</strong></p> <p>海神孕育了最初的生命，有一天，他来到人类部落，居住的淡水井边，误以为海水吸食后，肚腹疼痛不已，诞生下海女——希雅。从此，这井成了连通这个现世与异界的桥梁。希雅，则因为是淡水与海相结合的产物，不能随海回到大洋中。</p> <p>可每要等二十年旋转周期，井口才能与异世界的河流沟通。为缓解思念之情，海神特意造了一把钥匙。钥匙可以打开海城墙的一个出口，一经打开便是一月时间。城墙开启这段时间，现世、异界可以自由往来，因此海神专门在城墙内训练构建了一支部队：城墙守卫军，特意守护。洞悉世间万物，需要驰骋于大洋之中。离别之际，海神将女儿也一并交由城墙守卫军，代为看管。</p> <p>希雅的出生，喻义水生动物开始过度向陆地爬行生活。钥匙是全诗的关键。薨，海神的第七个儿子。因不满父亲的统治，杀死了海，并一并处决了其剩下的六个儿子。此时他还并不知道墙内的世界与钥匙的存在。</p> <p>马修，另一个异界（大洋）的来客。全诗，一处魂归于天，只是一种委婉的说辞，实际上是离开这个大洋，回归到另外一个大洋。主要人物之一。相对城墙内的人类居民，大洋人（局外人）一直都存在。</p> <p>（注：人物关系。大洋居民，成年后，可以自由出入墙内外两个世界，不受额外条件的限制。城墙内的居民，则不可以。条件限制包括：年龄，钥匙，以及旋转周期——时间的限制。）</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Ocean God, Hong, Matthew, Sea and others</strong></p> <p>The Ocean god gave birth to the first life. One day, he came to the human tribe, living by the freshwater well, mistaking the sea water for food, and suffered from stomach pain. He gave birth to a sea girl – Sea. Since then, this well has become a bridge connecting this world and the otherworld. Sea, because she is a product of the combination of freshwater and sea, cannot return to the ocean with the ocean.</p> <p>But every twenty years of rotation cycle, the well mouth can communicate with the river in the otherworld. To ease the longing, the Ocean god specially made a key. The key can open an exit of the sea wall, which is one month long once opened. During this time, the world and the otherworld can come and go freely, so the Ocean god specially trained a team in the wall: the wall guard army, to protect it. To understand everything in the world, you need to gallop in the ocean. At the time of departure, the Ocean god also handed his daughter to the wall guard army for custody.</p> <p>Sea’s birth symbolizes that aquatic animals began to crawl on land excessively. The key is the key to the whole poem. Hong, the seventh son of the Ocean god. Dissatisfied with his father’s rule, he killed the Ocean and executed his remaining six sons. At this time, he did not know the existence of the world inside the wall and the key.</p> <p>Matthew, another visitor from another world (ocean). In the whole poem, returning to heaven is just a euphemism for leaving this ocean and returning to another ocean. One of the main characters. Compared with the human residents inside the wall, ocean people (outsiders) have always existed.</p> <p>(Note: The relationship between characters. Ocean residents can freely enter and exit both worlds inside and outside the wall after they grow up, without being restricted by additional conditions. Residents inside the wall cannot. The conditions include: age, key, and rotation cycle – time limit.)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-12-10-characters-relationship-residents-inside-the-wall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-12-10-characters-relationship-residents-inside-the-wall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2017-12-10-characters-relationship-residents-inside-the-wall/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p><strong>怛、王国居民、城墙守卫军、各部落族群等</strong></p> <p>海城墙战役过去后的几十年时间，一个繁荣壮大的墙内王国诞生了。王国里，君主和他善良、可爱的妻子，辛勤耕耘着他们的土地。宛若，母系社会的美好生活。但是王城四周仍有许多大小、善恶不一的部落族群。国王，誓要征服、并统一他们，给未来的人们，创造出和平美好年代。</p> <p>在海神被薨王击败以后，海城墙落入了邪恶黑暗势力怛的手中。薨，在征服海城墙之南的各部途中，与王国北方族群缔结了婚约，有了他第一个“人类”儿子，怛。后来，薨回到他最初的领地；随着时间流逝，怛，逐渐成为海城墙权利最高的一方君主。</p> <p>同时，随着海城墙的失守，海神（Ocean）的女儿，希雅，被薨囚禁关押于海城墙某个隐秘的牢狱之中。马修和城墙守卫士兵，曾多次想方设法营救，但都未有建树。直到最近一次惊险的营救行动，然而最终，却将战火蔓延到了新的人类王国。时值王国北方族群，已经加入邪恶薨、怛的阵营。迷蒙森林，也抵挡不住他们前行的脚步。</p> <p>经过惨烈的王国战役，马修、城墙守卫军们和一并战斗的王国居民，承受了巨大损失。希雅，被再次俘虏；王国君主，留下他善良、可爱的妻儿，匆匆离世。马修的尸体，也一并与国王安葬在一起，于迷蒙森林之中。</p> <p>只剩下一些残存的城墙守卫将士们，带着宝贵物件，逃亡不知所踪的南方海洋。过着鲜为人知的避世生活。最后，逐渐长大的王子，期待重现王国的繁荣。</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Da, the Kingdom Residents, the Wall Guard Army, Various Tribal Groups, etc.</strong></p> <p>In the decades after the Sea Wall battle, a prosperous and powerful kingdom was born inside the wall. In the kingdom, the monarch and his kind and lovely wife worked hard on their land. It was like a beautiful life in a matriarchal society. But there are still many large and small, good and evil tribal groups around the king city. The king vowed to conquer and unify them, and create a peaceful and beautiful era for future generations.</p> <p>After the Ocean God was defeated by King Hong, the Sea Wall fell into the hands of Da, an evil dark force. Hong, on his way to conquer the various tribes south of the Sea Wall, married a northern tribe of the Kingdom and had his first “human” son, Da. Later, Hong returned to his original territory; as time passed, Da gradually became the supreme lord of the Sea Wall.</p> <p>At the same time, after the fall of the Sea Wall, the daughter of the Ocean God, Sea, was imprisoned in a secret prison inside the Sea Wall. Matthew and the wall guard soldiers tried many ways to rescue her, but they did not succeed. Until the recent thrilling rescue operation, but in the end, it spread the war to the new human kingdom. At this time, the northern tribes of the Kingdom had already joined the evil Hong and Da’s camp. The misty forest could not stop their footsteps.</p> <p>After a fierce battle in the Kingdom, Matthew, the wall guard army and the Kingdom residents who fought with them suffered huge losses. Sea was captured again; the Kingdom monarch left his kind and lovely wife and son and died hastily. Matthew’s body was also buried with the king in the misty forest.</p> <p>Only a few remaining wall guard soldiers escaped with valuable items to the unknown southern ocean. They lived a secluded life that few people knew about. Finally, the prince who grew up gradually hoped to restore the prosperity of the Kingdom.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-07-17-mouthpiece-of-power-patriots-big-v/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-07-17-mouthpiece-of-power-patriots-big-v</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-07-17-mouthpiece-of-power-patriots-big-v/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>指望“爱国大V”们（假爱国）关注，对外影响不好的大事，那是在茅坑里打电筒——（找屎）。Ta们爱的不是国，更不是她的国民；而是向上的权力，是打着爱国主义旗帜，挂人民路灯而非“资本家”（广义）的蛀虫、真流氓。</p> <hr/> <p>Expect the “Patriots Big V” (Fake Patriots) to pay attention to a major event with bad external influence, that is to turn on a flashlight in the toilet — (looking for shit). What they love is not the country, let alone her citizens; but the upward power, hanging the people on the street lamps, under the banner of patriotism, rather than the “capitalists”, they are worms and real hooligans.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-09-05-paradox-of-human-nature-the-dialectic-between-straight-and-twisted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-09-05-paradox-of-human-nature-the-dialectic-between-straight-and-twisted</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-09-05-paradox-of-human-nature-the-dialectic-between-straight-and-twisted/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>人性，本质上很纠结。双重、多重性格，不可避免。好的、坏的；又好、又坏；不好、不坏；又不好，又不坏……相对笔直，绝对扭曲。不清不楚，不明不白。对人性进行探讨，本质上是在反人性。与其探讨，不如反。反也是一种探讨……</p> <hr/> <p>Human Nature is intrinsically tangled. Dual and multiple personalities are inevitable. Good, bad; and good, and bad; not good, not bad; and not good, and not bad… Relatively straight, absolutely twisted. Unclear, Ununderstand. Discussion of human nature is essentially anti-it. It is better to anti than discuss. Anti is also a discussion…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-11-19-hypothesis-meaning-of-death/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-11-19-hypothesis-meaning-of-death</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2021-11-19-hypothesis-meaning-of-death/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p><strong>假使当你明白</strong>，人类存在于这个世界上，根本没有任何意义。以后，你就会觉得，你可以什么都不用期待，也没有任何必要。什么喜乐悲欢、俗世凡尘，通通都与你无关。</p> <p>当你明白，<strong>死亡是人类活着唯一有意义的事情</strong>以后。你就会觉得，死亡其实是一种解脱、一种恩赐。人类生下来，目的就是为着死亡。所以，ta们压根没有出生的必要。</p> <p><strong>但是，你不明白</strong>。所以你拼了命去，活着，一定要证明一些什么。比如，繁衍。能证明什么呢？上亿年的人类历史……？</p> <p>你不明白人类活着的意义是什么。<strong>长生不老</strong>？约等于，死亡后的灵魂？你不明白。所以你行尸走肉般的活着。又假使你末了终于明白。<strong>死亡是证明你活过的最大意义！</strong>你死亡，你获得了永生。</p> <hr/> <p><strong>If you understand,</strong> that human existence in this world has no meaning at all. Then, you will feel that you don’t have to expect anything, and there is no need. All the joys and sorrows, worldly things, have nothing to do with you.</p> <p>When you understand that <strong>death is the only meaningful thing for human beings to live</strong>. You will feel that death is actually a relief, a gift. Human beings are born for the purpose of dying. So, they don’t need to be born at all.</p> <p><strong>But you don’t understand.</strong> So you try your best to live, to prove something. For example, reproduction. What can it prove? The history of human beings for hundreds of millions of years…?</p> <p>You don’t understand the meaning of human life. <strong>Immortality</strong>? Equivalent to, the soul after death? You don’t understand. So you live like a walking dead. And if you finally understand at the end. <strong>Death is the greatest meaning of proving that you have lived!</strong> You die, you get eternal life.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-02-23-dialogue-mouth-cannon-with-officials-and-capitalists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-02-23-dialogue-mouth-cannon-with-officials-and-capitalists</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-02-23-dialogue-mouth-cannon-with-officials-and-capitalists/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>抢占ta们信仰、道德的至高点</p> <h2 id="嘴炮与官员">嘴炮与官员</h2> <p>您是人民么？<br/> 您的信仰是什么？<br/> 您为谁服务？<br/> 您不是人民，那么您是谁？<br/> 您是境外势力派来祸害母国人民的反动派么？<br/> 难道您不为人民服务，是为资本家？</p> <h2 id="嘴炮与资本家">嘴炮与资本家</h2> <p>您是人民么？<br/> 您有道德底线么？<br/> 您也敢这么大张旗鼓地搞剥削，在社会主义国家？<br/> 您不是人民，那么您是黄世仁？<br/> 您就不怕官员，杀您的头、抄您的家么？<br/> 难道您的保护伞，就是官员？</p> <hr/> <p>Occupying the highest point of their faith, morality</p> <h2 id="mouth-cannon-and-officials">Mouth cannon and officials</h2> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Are you the people?
What is your faith?
Who do you serve?
You are not the people, then who are you?
Are you a reactionary sent by foreign forces to harm the people of your motherland?
Don’t you serve the people, but the capitalists?
</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="mouth-cannon-and-capitalists">Mouth cannon and capitalists</h2> <p>Are you the people?<br/> Do you have a moral bottom line?<br/> How dare you exploit so openly in a socialist country?<br/> You are not the people, then are you Huang Shiren?<br/> Are you not afraid of the officials, killing your head, ransacking your home?<br/> Is your umbrella, the official?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-06-11-group-society-consumption-and-tragedy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-06-11-group-society-consumption-and-tragedy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2022-06-11-group-society-consumption-and-tragedy/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>世界本没有错，单一个体也没有；错的是，ta们构成的群体。群体社会：无限内耗，又或者，需要转移某种影响。于是注定了，每天都有悲剧事件产生。</p> <hr/> <p>There is nothing wrong with the world, nor with an individual; what is wrong is the group they form. Group society: infinite consumption, or the need to transfer some kind of influence. As a result, tragedies are bound to happen every day.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-06-having-a-choice-from-specific-individuals-to-abstract-history/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-06-having-a-choice-from-specific-individuals-to-abstract-history</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-06-having-a-choice-from-specific-individuals-to-abstract-history/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>对某一件事的看法？往往，我都站“有得选”的一方。“劳东燕”和“胡锡进”们，各自确实有着“专属的蠢”，但ta们也有一个共同点，就是会尝试从其它角度，提供一些不同的选择。相比较，一开始同样是“一条道走到黑，只坚持有一个标准答案存在”的其ta选手，两者似乎“聪慧”了许多。</p> <p>回看“这类人”曾经过往的遭遇（右派分子），见证目前和未来将要面临的可能（右倾的左派），也就瞥见了几分历史的发展与进程。</p> <hr/> <p>Opinion on a certain matter? Often, I stand on the side of ‘having a choice.’ People like Lao Dongyan and Hu Xijin each have their own ‘unique foolishness’, but they also share a common trait: they try to provide different options from other perspectives. Compared to those who insist on a single standard answer from the beginning, these two seem much ‘smarter.’</p> <p>Looking back at the past experiences of such people (rightists) and witnessing the possibilities they face now and in the future (left-leaning rightists), one can catch a glimpse of the development and progress of history.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-07-left-and-right-praise-and-criticism-from-tail-to-mental-illness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-07-left-and-right-praise-and-criticism-from-tail-to-mental-illness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-07-left-and-right-praise-and-criticism-from-tail-to-mental-illness/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>极左：赞美不彻底，彻底不赞美。“唯一”指导方针。<br/> 左派：赞美是最重要的工作。<br/> 右倾的左派：赞美是主要工作，适当批评。<br/> 中间派：该赞美赞美、该批评批评（理想情况）；夹着尾巴做人（现实处境）。<br/> 左倾的右派：批评是主要工作，适当赞美。<br/> 右派：批评是最重要的工作。<br/> 极右：批评不彻底，彻底不批评。“造反”唯一成功道路。</p> <p>极左等于极右，“唯一”指导方针等于“造反”唯一成功道路。</p> <p>中国历史上去找“极右极左”集大成者的典型代表，绕不开“嬴政、刘邦、朱元璋、毛泽东”这几个名字。除了以上这类，有严重人格和心理方面问题的“天才疾病选手”，以及“岁静的中间派”，其它也都或多或少，“被逼着”患上了不同程度精神方面的疾病。</p> <p>而，世间本没有左右、中间，没有派别，人也应当没有尾巴。夹着尾巴做人，那不一样还是猴子么！</p> <hr/> <p>Extreme Left: Incomplete praise, thoroughly incomplete praise. The “only” guiding principle. Left-wing: Praise is the most important task. Right-leaning Left-wing: Praise is the primary task, with appropriate criticism.</p> <p>Centrist: Praise when it’s due, criticize when it’s due (ideal situation); live with your tail between your legs (realistic situation).</p> <p>Left-leaning Right-wing: Criticism is the primary task, with appropriate praise. Right-wing: Criticism is the most important task. Extreme Right: Incomplete criticism, thoroughly incomplete criticism. “Rebellion” is the only successful path.</p> <p>Extreme Left = Extreme Right, “only” guiding principle = “Rebellion” is the only successful path.</p> <p>In Chinese history, if we were to search for typical representatives of “extreme right and extreme left,” the names “Ying Zheng (Qin Shi Huang), Liu Bang, Zhu Yuanzhang, Mao Zedong” cannot be overlooked. Apart from these, there are also those “genius figures” with serious personality and psychological issues, as well as “passive centrists.” Everyone else has, to a greater or lesser degree, been “forced” into various degrees of mental illness.</p> <p>In reality, there is no such thing as left, right, or center; no factions. People should not have tails. To live with one’s tail between their legs, isn’t that just like a monkey?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-26-dream-in-a-dream-ghost-doll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T21:15:14-07:00</updated><id>https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-26-dream-in-a-dream-ghost-doll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://36525.day/blog/2025-06-21/2024-08-26-dream-in-a-dream-ghost-doll/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/blog/" style="width:100%;" alt=""/></p> <p>一天，孙婆带着她的家人以及半岁小孩去爬山。小孩光着脚丫屁颠屁颠走在长满杂草的小道。我跟在小孩最后边。小孩要求抱抱，前面的其它孩子已经走很快，隔了有一段路程了。无奈，只好有我来，担负这个责任。</p> <p>这便恰好成了后续梦中所有恐怖故事的源头。</p> <p>抱在手里的半岁娃娃，不知怎的全身异常柔软，跟一泥鳅似的，更像一人头蛇身的妖怪，变换各种手位，终究来回缩动。走在前面的孙婆以及其ta比较大的孩子们，远处发现纷纷停下了脚步。其中，年龄比较大的一个孩子，指责我抱孩子的方式不对。当孩子交给ta手中，孩子又重新恢复了原样。然后，半岁小孩继续跟在了ta们身后。</p> <p>事后，大家各自回到各自某个家里。夜晚，半岁小孩突然闯入我的梦境，好似白天夜间的小路，我欺负了ta一般。是要报复给我留下深刻不灭的印象。</p> <p>先是小孩开始钻进我的被窝，趴在我身上，变成一滩粘长的物体。吓得我双脚双手，分别尝试蹬开和甩走沉重的被窝与附着的物体。当我又在尝试睁开眼睛的其它瞬间，发现鬼魅的眼睛在盯着我。我定了定神，看见自家的天花板，回到了真实世界。我舒了口气，急忙又重新睡了过去。当我再次睁眼，发现变成了其它鬼魅在眼睛直勾勾地盯着我。ta们没有眼睛，感觉比先前半岁光脚走在山野小道的娃娃，看起来还要恐怖。</p> <p>我重新定了定神，尝试写下梦中的这一境遇。</p> <hr/> <p>One day, Sun Po brought her family along with her half-year-old child to climb a mountain. The child, barefoot, toddled along a path overgrown with weeds, bouncing along in a carefree manner. I followed behind, trailing last. The child requested to be carried, but the other children ahead had already walked quite a distance. With no other choice, it fell to me to take on that responsibility.</p> <p>And so, this moment became the origin of all the terrifying stories that would haunt my dreams later.</p> <p>The child in my arms, for reasons unknown, felt unusually limp—soft like a mudfish, almost like a creature with a human head and a serpent’s body, shifting its position in my grasp, wriggling back and forth. The others in front, including Sun Po and the older children, noticed from a distance and stopped. One of the older children scolded me for holding the baby incorrectly. When the child was handed over to them, it returned to its usual form. Then, the half-year-old child continued to follow behind them.</p> <p>Later, everyone returned to their respective homes. That night, the half-year-old child suddenly appeared in my dream, like the small road from the day, as if I had wronged it. It seemed to want to exact a deep, unshakable vengeance on me.</p> <p>First, the child crawled into my bed, lying on top of me, transforming into a long, sticky mass. Terrified, I tried to kick and fling the heavy blanket and its attached weight off me. In another attempt to open my eyes, I saw a ghostly set of eyes staring at me. I steadied myself and found I was looking at my own ceiling, returning to the real world. I sighed in relief, quickly falling back asleep. But when I opened my eyes again, I found other ghostly figures staring at me with piercing, hollow eyes. They had no eyes, and somehow, they seemed even more terrifying than the half-year-old child who had toddled barefoot on the mountain trail.</p> <p>I steadied myself once more, trying to write down the strange experience of this dream.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>