<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://100-y.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>以「36525 天」为象征，这是某人用一生在写的一本书。Symbolizing 36,525 days — a book someone writes across a lifetime. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">100-Y · GitHub</title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100-Y · GitHub"/><published>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y--github</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/100-y-github/"><![CDATA[<p>We read every piece of feedback, and take your input very seriously. To see all available qualifiers, see our documentation.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>        Prevent this user from interacting with your repositories and sending you notifications.
      Learn more about blocking users.
    
          You must be logged in to block users.
        
    Contact GitHub support about this user’s behavior.
    Learn more about reporting abuse.
  
        ……
</code></pre></div></div> <p>HTML</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>              There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[100-Y has one repository available. Follow their code on GitHub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2017-10-12-rivers-in-life-ghost-and-me/"><![CDATA[<p>生命中的河流，密密麻麻，挤满了各式各样的人形动物肢体；<br/> 无知的人们以为是珍奇鱼类，纷纷将他们打捞上岸。<br/> 有的已“死”去多时，有的还在拼命挣扎着跳入水中；<br/> 我一边阻挠这“愚蠢”行为，一边发现岸边浮沉一颗眨眼的少女头颅……</p> <p>我走近，万分惊恐，尝试用简短的英文与她交谈：<br/> 她说她来自日本，错过了这次赶胎时间；<br/> 以半人形模样委身鱼类，而再次苟活人间。<br/> 可我疑问“你却来到中国的河流？“<br/> 她又说：下次新生时间在123天以后，之前，她务必赶往所到之处。<br/> 我又无知了！决定帮助她完成这一艰难使程……</p> <p>于是、忽然。她冰凉的身体，伸出一支手来，<br/> 搭在我左边胳膊的窝心处：<br/> 这一直接行为，吓得我慌乱，差点坠入那该死的河中……<br/> 我想我是要被鬼迷心窍，然后，我醒了！</p> <ul> <li>Rivers in life, densely, packed with all kinds of humanoid animal limbs;</li> <li>Ignorant people think they are rare fishes, and salvaging them ashore one after another.</li> <li>Some have been “dead” for a long time, some are still struggling desperately to jump into the water;</li> <li> <p>On the one hand, i was trying to obstruct this “stupid” behavior, at the same time, i found a blinking young girl’s head floating and sinking on the shore…</p> </li> <li>As i approached, i was terrified, trying to talk to her in short english:</li> <li>She say she is from japan, missed the delivery time;</li> <li>Turn into a fish in half-human form. and live the world again.</li> <li>But i doubt “why you come to the river of china?”</li> <li>She added: the next newborn time is 123 days later, before that, she must rush wherever she goes.</li> <li> <p>I’m ignorant again! deciding to help her complete this difficult journey…</p> </li> <li>So, all of a sudden. her cold body stretched out a hand,</li> <li>Put it on the center of my left arm:</li> <li>This direct behavior scared me into a panic. almost fell into the damn river…</li> <li>I think i’m going to be fascinated by ghosts, then i woke up!</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-distant-gentleness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-distant-gentleness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-distant-gentleness/"><![CDATA[<p>在那光影交错的黄昏里，<br/> 你是隐匿于风中的一抹温柔，<br/> 一只轻触便溶于掌心的蝶。</p> <p>世上无数深渊，闪烁着暗流的诱惑，<br/> 可我愿坠落，只为那一瞬间的沉醉。<br/> 那并非救赎，亦非枷锁，<br/> 而是两颗灵魂在无言中擦肩，<br/> 却不愿回头的怅然与遗憾。</p> <p>你是冬日的雾，薄如纱、冷如铁，<br/> 却在夜的边缘散发出微弱的光。<br/> 每一步接近，都仿佛触及虚空，<br/> 又仿佛走进无边的荒野，<br/> 渴望、畏惧、无从逃避。</p> <p>我在你的影子里沉浮，<br/> 像在海面上漂泊的孤舟，<br/> 波澜过后，依旧是沉默的深蓝。<br/> 你走近时，世间寂静无声，<br/> 离去时，所有的星光都失了颜色。</p> <p>我们之间没有承诺，<br/> 亦无期盼，只有一抹悠长的哀愁，<br/> 像秋叶飘落，<br/> 在风中旋转，沉默，最终化为尘埃。</p> <p>而我知晓，在你触不可及的彼岸，<br/> 某种温柔的痛楚会永存，<br/> 像一道浅浅的疤痕，无法愈合，<br/> 却是我唯一的纪念。</p> <ul> <li>In the Twilight of Intertwined Shadows</li> <li>In the twilight of intertwined shadows,</li> <li>you are a touch of gentleness hidden in the breeze,</li> <li> <p>a butterfly that melts at the slightest touch.</p> </li> <li>The world holds countless depths, flashing with dark allure,</li> <li>yet I would fall, just for that brief moment of intoxication.</li> <li>It is neither redemption nor a chain,</li> <li>but two souls brushing silently past each other,</li> <li> <p>unwilling to turn back, bound by longing and regret.</p> </li> <li>You are the winter fog, thin as gauze, cold as steel,</li> <li>casting faint light at the edge of night.</li> <li>Each step closer feels like reaching into emptiness,</li> <li>like entering an endless wilderness—</li> <li> <p>a place of desire, fear, and inescapable mystery.</p> </li> <li>I drift within your shadow,</li> <li>like a lone boat adrift on silent, deep blue waves.</li> <li>When you approach, the world holds its breath;</li> <li> <p>when you leave, all the stars lose their color.</p> </li> <li>There are no promises between us,</li> <li>no expectations, only a lingering sorrow,</li> <li>like autumn leaves falling,</li> <li> <p>spiraling in the wind, silent, and becoming dust.</p> </li> <li>And I know, in that unreachable distance,</li> <li>a tender ache will forever remain,</li> <li>like a faint scar that cannot heal,</li> <li>and yet, it is my only keepsake.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-the-illiterate-may-not-read-but-a-diploma-will-be-fine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-the-illiterate-may-not-read-but-a-diploma-will-be-fine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-08-the-illiterate-may-not-read-but-a-diploma-will-be-fine/"><![CDATA[<p>发文凭，不过是蒙上一层光鲜的外衣，把无知装扮成一张无害的证书。可字里行间的空白，像是静默的荒野。证书在手，真相却无处可藏——那是一场自欺的盛宴，是无知在礼堂中央的舞步，背后是知识的缺席，是思想的荒芜。</p> <p>真正的教育，不在那一纸文凭，而在于眼中的光芒、心中的热忱，甚至是那一刻理解世界的顿悟。文凭是门口的木牌，而识字，是踏入真知之门的钥匙。</p> <hr/> <p>A diploma is nothing more than a shiny exterior, a way to dress ignorance up as a harmless certificate. But the blank spaces between the lines are like silent wastelands. With the certificate in hand, the truth has nowhere to hide—it is a feast of self-deception, ignorance dancing at the center of the hall, while behind it lies the absence of knowledge and the desolation of thought.</p> <p>True education is not in that piece of paper, but in the light in one’s eyes, the passion in one’s heart, and even in that moment of sudden understanding of the world. A diploma is merely a wooden sign at the door, while literacy is the key to entering the gate of true knowledge.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-10-if-lu-xun-is-the-black-of-chinese-then-what-is-hu-shi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-10-if-lu-xun-is-the-black-of-chinese-then-what-is-hu-shi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-10-if-lu-xun-is-the-black-of-chinese-then-what-is-hu-shi/"><![CDATA[<p>将鲁迅视作“支黑”，无非是在他冷峻、批判的文字里捕捉到了一种直面民族弊病的决绝态度——如同医者的锐利刀锋，切割出一片自我剖析的伤口，让民族能见血、见骨。而胡适呢？他或许是“支灰”。不同于鲁迅的尖锐反叛，胡适倾向温和的改良与包容的西化。胡适主张渐进地改变现实，既认可传统价值，又大胆接纳西方文明。他的姿态像是温吞的灰色，似远不似近的幽暗。他不摧毁，而是温柔劝解；不怒目相视，而是和颜而对。</p> <p>他与鲁迅之间的差异就如一幅光影对比鲜明的油画：鲁迅是浓烈的黑，深刻而不可妥协；胡适则是柔和的灰，既保留了东方的意象，又允许外来思想的渗透。</p> <hr/> <p>To regard Lu Xun as the “the black of Chinese” is merely to capture, in his cold and critical writings, a decisive attitude towards confronting the nation’s ailments — like the sharp scalpel of a doctor, cutting open a wound of self-analysis that allows the nation to see its blood and bones. But what about Hu Shi? Perhaps he is “the gray of Chinese.” Unlike Lu Xun’s sharp rebellion, Hu Shi leaned towards gentle reform and a tolerant Westernization. Hu Shi advocated for gradual change, recognizing traditional values while boldly accepting Western civilization. His stance resembles a subdued gray, a dimness that feels distant yet close. He did not destroy, but gently persuaded; he did not glare in anger, but responded with a friendly face.</p> <p>The difference between him and Lu Xun is like a vivid oil painting of contrasting light and shadow: Lu Xun is a deep, uncompromising black, while Hu Shi is a soft gray, preserving Eastern imagery while allowing foreign ideas to seep in.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-a-short-piece-on-dogs-chasing-science/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-a-short-piece-on-dogs-chasing-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-a-short-piece-on-dogs-chasing-science/"><![CDATA[<p>夜深，废弃的广场上，一团漂浮的“科学”悄然现身，像一段未解的公式，摇曳在月光下。一群流浪狗缓缓围拢过来，眼中闪着迷惘的光芒。科学时而飘忽，时而停驻，像在挑衅，又似在引诱。狗们缓慢地追逐，瘦骨嶙峋的身影在光圈里拉得长长，仿佛紧抓着某种命运的尾巴。</p> <p>人们从广场外走过，嘲笑着这荒诞的场景，转身离去。狗继续追，科学继续飘。天亮时，狗群四散而去，留下空荡的广场，和空气中一丝虚无的气味。</p> <hr/> <p>Late at night, in the abandoned square, a floating “science” quietly emerges, like an unsolved equation, swaying under the moonlight. A group of stray dogs slowly gathers around, their eyes gleaming with a confused light. Science drifts intermittently, sometimes fleeting, sometimes pausing, as if provoking or perhaps enticing. The dogs chase slowly, their emaciated figures elongated in the halo of light, as if desperately clutching the tail of some fate.</p> <p>People walk by the square, mocking the absurd scene, and turn away. The dogs continue their pursuit, science continues to float. By dawn, the pack disperses, leaving behind an empty square and a faint smell of emptiness lingering in the air.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-the-interpretation-of-random-mass-incidents-and-their-social-implications/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-the-interpretation-of-random-mass-incidents-and-their-social-implications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-11-the-interpretation-of-random-mass-incidents-and-their-social-implications/"><![CDATA[<p>随机群发事件通常被视为“个体偶然行为”，这一解读反映了社会对集体困境和系统性问题的回避倾向。通过简化为个体的偶然选择，社会避免了对结构性问题的深刻反思，也忽略了共性痛点的存在。</p> <p><strong>核心现象与根源：</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>现象</strong>：社会倾向将行为归因于个体心理或临时情绪，忽视群体间普遍的不满和压抑。</li> <li><strong>根源</strong>：这种“个体偶然”论调成为回避工具，将群体性问题伪装为孤立事件，减弱反思的紧迫性。</li> </ul> <p><strong>后果与本质：</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>后果</strong>：责任被稀释，系统性裂缝被掩盖。</li> <li><strong>本质</strong>：群发事件的频率揭示了个体间的共同情感——不满、孤独与疏离。</li> </ul> <p><strong>总结：</strong>“个体偶然”论调不过是对群体困境的温和逃避，掩盖了深层的社会裂痕与制度性缺陷。</p> <hr/> <p>Random mass incidents are often labeled as “individual random acts,” reflecting a societal tendency to avoid confronting collective struggles and systemic issues. By attributing these events to individual choices, society evades deep reflection on structural problems and neglects shared pain points.</p> <p><strong>Core Phenomenon and Causes:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Phenomenon</strong>: Behavior is attributed to personal psychology or temporary emotions, overlooking widespread dissatisfaction and repression within groups.</li> <li><strong>Causes</strong>: The “individual randomness” narrative serves as an evasion tool, disguising collective problems as isolated cases and reducing the urgency for societal introspection.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Consequences and Essence:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Consequences</strong>: Responsibility is diluted, and systemic cracks remain concealed.</li> <li><strong>Essence</strong>: The frequent occurrence of such incidents reveals shared emotions among individuals—dissatisfaction, loneliness, and alienation.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> The “individual randomness” narrative is merely a gentle form of evasion, masking deeper social fractures and systemic flaws.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-li-ziqis-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-li-ziqis-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-li-ziqis-work/"><![CDATA[<p>李子柒的作品如田园诗般唯美，每一帧都像静谧的画卷，勾勒出人们对自然和乡土的渴望。她用精致的镜头、自然的光影、细腻的构图，将古老生活的宁静与和谐展现得淋漓尽致。</p> <p>然而，这种美好却带着一丝疏离感，宛如遥远的桃源。它吸引人，但仿佛是对现代生活的一种逃离之梦，令人感到美丽而又无法触及。</p> <hr/> <p>Li Ziqi’s work is as poetic as an idyllic landscape, each frame like a serene painting that captures people’s yearning for nature and rural roots. With refined camera work, natural lighting, and delicate compositions, she vividly portrays the tranquility and harmony of a bygone life.</p> <p>Yet, this beauty carries a touch of detachment, like a distant paradise. It enchants, but feels like a dream of escape from modern life—captivating, yet just out of reach.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-the-echo-of-the-lost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-the-echo-of-the-lost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-12-the-echo-of-the-lost/"><![CDATA[<p>在一个阴云密布的黄昏，湿润的空气中弥漫着草木的气息。一条狭窄的小路穿越在荒野之间，两旁是枝条纠缠的古老树林，树叶似乎在无声地低语。微弱的光线透过密集的枝叶洒在泥土上，点点光斑在风的轻拂下摇曳不定。远处，有一座孤独的小屋，烟囱里飘出的袅袅炊烟如同一丝记忆的残余，仿佛在召唤着某个失落的故事，而你却无法触及它的起点。</p> <p>你缓步走近那座小屋，脚下的土地松软，随着每一步，泥土轻微地弹起，仿佛地面也在记忆的重负下微微颤抖。空气中弥漫着不知名的花香，夹杂着一丝霉味。远离了繁杂的世界，这片寂静中，却又像是某种无形的力量在悄悄逼近，紧紧包围着你。</p> <p>小屋的窗子破旧，木窗框的油漆早已剥落，露出下面斑驳的木质纹理。窗内，似乎有某种暗影在游移。你忍不住加快步伐，心脏的跳动在耳边回响，甚至让你开始怀疑，这片寂静是否早已被某种久远的记忆所侵占。</p> <p>突然，一声低沉的嘎吱声打破了沉默，仿佛是木门在无人的操控下轻轻打开。你站住了，目光不自觉地投向那扇门，心中莫名涌起一阵焦虑与好奇。门背后，黑暗似乎在等待着某个答案。</p> <p>你迈开步伐，推开那扇沉重的木门，门轴发出长长的哀鸣。屋内的空气沉闷，弥漫着发霉的木材与旧纸的气息。四周一片昏暗，唯一的光源是从破碎窗户中透进来的微弱余晖。屋内并无任何家具，只有一张被灰尘覆盖的地毯，仿佛曾经是某个温暖家庭的一部分。你不由自主地俯身，双手触及那块尘封已久的织物，指尖感受到的是岁月的残痕和曾经的温度。</p> <p>突然，你的眼睛被一处角落吸引，那里有一个小小的木箱，显得与周围的空旷格格不入。箱子的表面陈旧斑驳，上面雕刻着一些模糊不清的符号，像是某种早已被遗忘的语言。你轻轻地打开箱子，心中忽然升起一种无名的恐惧。箱子里静静地躺着一封信，信封上没有任何标记，只有一条被时间腐蚀的红绸带。</p> <p>你的手微微颤抖，拆开了信封。信纸已经泛黄，字迹模糊，但依然能够辨认出那熟悉的笔迹。那是你父亲的字迹——从未见过的字句：“当你找到这封信时，记住，你并不孤单。这个地方，曾经属于你。”</p> <p>你的心猛然一震，似乎有某种深藏的记忆在逐渐浮现，而它正紧紧地纠缠着你。当你继续读下去时，字句越来越清晰：“所有的故事，都将在这里开始，永远无法结束。”</p> <p>你愣在那里，空气突然变得凝重，仿佛整个屋子都开始窒息。那句“所有的故事，都将在这里开始，永远无法结束”像一道无形的锁链，锁住了你的心脏，让你无法动弹。你不禁低头望向信纸，脑海中乱作一团，父亲早已离世，而这封信，显然早在他离开前就已写好。那么，这究竟是怎样的预兆？为什么它在现在出现在你的手中？</p> <p>忽然，一阵冷风从屋外吹入，窗户微微晃动，随即猛地关上。你转身，感觉到那暗影再次在角落里动了动。不是幻觉，你清晰地看到一双眼睛，深邃如夜，正在静静注视着你。它们没有生气，也没有恶意，仿佛是某种无形的存在在等待着你做出决定。</p> <p>你小心地走向那眼睛的源头，发现它并非真实的眼睛，而是一面古老的镜子。镜子的表面布满了岁月的痕迹，边缘的铜框已经腐蚀，反射出的光线如同一池死水。你不禁凑近了些，突然，镜中的倒影开始变得模糊，像是烟雾在翻滚，而其中显现出你自己，却又不完全是你。那影像中的你，身穿另一套衣服，眼神冰冷，嘴角带着一丝诡异的笑容。</p> <p>“你终于来了。” 镜中的你低声说道，声音沙哑，却清晰可辨。</p> <p>你猛地后退，胸口一阵剧烈的跳动，心脏仿佛要从喉咙里跳出来。镜中的你继续说道：“这是你早已注定的结局。你所寻找的答案，不仅仅是关于你父亲，而是关于你自己的过去。”</p> <p>这时，你的思绪一片混乱，然而，某种记忆如潮水般涌上心头——那种久远的、你早已遗忘的感觉。你意识到，你从未真正离开过这里。你和这座小屋，和那封信，早已在某种时间的循环中紧密相连。你是被命运所召唤回来，回到这个遗失的地方，去面对曾经未完的故事。</p> <p>镜中的笑容越来越显得诡异，渐渐地，它变得模糊，而你在镜子中的身影也开始扭曲。你用力抓住镜框，试图挣脱那深邃的幻象，但这时，一阵无法抗拒的力量将你拉入了镜中——如同被吞噬一般。</p> <p>你失去了知觉，黑暗吞噬了你的一切。许久之后，黑暗中传来一声轻微的叹息。镜面再次恢复了平静，镜中的你，再次回到最初的地方，静静地站在那里，等待着下一个人，来揭开那个不曾结束的谜团。</p> <hr/> <p>On a cloud-covered dusk, the moist air is filled with the scent of vegetation. A narrow path winds through the wilderness, flanked by ancient trees whose branches are tangled, their leaves whispering in silence. Faint light filters through the dense foliage, scattering patches on the ground, flickering gently in the breeze. In the distance, a solitary cabin stands with smoke curling softly from the chimney—a wisp of memory, as if calling forth a forgotten tale, one you can sense yet cannot touch the beginning of.</p> <p>You walk slowly toward the cabin, feeling the soft ground beneath your feet; with each step, the earth slightly gives, as if it too trembles under the weight of memory. The air is infused with an unknown floral scent, tinged with a hint of must. Far from the world’s clamor, this silence surrounds you, yet it feels as if something unseen is quietly pressing in, wrapping itself tightly around you.</p> <p>The cabin’s window is worn, its wooden frame flaking, exposing weathered grain beneath. Inside, a shadow seems to shift. You quicken your pace, the pounding of your heart echoing in your ears, making you wonder if this silence has long been occupied by some ancient memory.</p> <p>Suddenly, a low creak pierces the quiet—a door opening gently, as if by unseen hands. You stop, your gaze drawn toward the door, a strange mix of unease and curiosity rising within. Beyond that door, darkness seems to wait with an answer.</p> <p>You step forward, pushing open the heavy door, its hinges releasing a long groan. The air inside is stifling, heavy with the scent of decaying wood and old paper. The room is dimly lit, the only light seeping through a shattered window, casting a faint glow. There’s no furniture, only a dust-covered rug, a remnant of a time when this place was once warm. Almost instinctively, you kneel, fingers touching the fabric’s long-sealed threads, feeling the remnants of time and once-held warmth.</p> <p>Suddenly, your gaze catches on something in the corner—a small wooden box, out of place in the emptiness. Its surface is worn, carved with faded symbols, a language perhaps long forgotten. You open the box carefully, a nameless fear stirring within. Inside lies an old letter, unmarked except for a red ribbon, frayed by time.</p> <p>With trembling hands, you open the letter. The paper has yellowed, the ink faded, yet the handwriting remains recognizable—it’s your father’s, though you’ve never seen these words before: “When you find this, remember, you are not alone. This place once belonged to you.”</p> <p>Your heart pounds, as if some buried memory is awakening, threading itself around you. As you read further, the words grow clearer: “Every story begins here and will never end.”</p> <p>You stand frozen, feeling the air thicken as though the entire cabin is closing in on you. That line—“Every story begins here and will never end”—is like an invisible chain, binding your heart, rooting you in place. Staring down at the letter, your mind spins; your father has been gone for years, and yet this letter must have been left long before he passed. What could it possibly mean? Why did it find its way into your hands now?</p> <p>A chill breeze drifts in, rattling the window, which slams shut. Turning, you sense movement in the corner—a shadow shifting once more. Not a figment of your imagination; you clearly see a pair of eyes, deep as night, observing you. They’re neither alive nor hostile, merely the presence of something unseen, as if waiting for your decision.</p> <p>Slowly, you approach the source, only to realize they are not eyes but an ancient mirror. Its surface is etched with age, its copper frame corroded, reflecting light like a pool of stagnant water. Leaning closer, you notice the reflection morphing, smoke-like waves swirling within. There, you see yourself, but not quite you—the image stares back, cold-eyed, with a faint, eerie smile.</p> <p>“You’ve finally arrived,” it says in a raspy voice, though the words are unmistakable.</p> <p>Your pulse races, chest tightening as if your heart is climbing into your throat. The figure in the mirror continues, “This is the fate set for you. The answers you seek aren’t just about your father; they are the keys to your own past.”</p> <p>Your mind spins, memories surfacing like waves—lost fragments, long-buried sensations. You realize, you never truly left this place. You, the cabin, and this letter are all woven into a cycle of time, calling you back to face an unfinished story.</p> <p>The figure’s smile twists, and it begins to fade, your reflection distorting. Grasping the mirror’s edge, you struggle against the dark pull, but a force beyond resistance drags you into its depths—as though swallowed whole.</p> <p>You lose all awareness as darkness envelopes you. After a long silence, a soft sigh echoes in the black. The mirror’s surface returns to stillness, and there you stand, waiting once again for the next seeker to unravel this never-ending mystery.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-13-family-scandal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=""/><published>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T18:58:56+00:00</updated><id>https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-13-family-scandal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://100-y.github.io/blog/2025/2024-11-13-family-scandal/"><![CDATA[<p>家丑，总在遮蔽中沉默。每一次真相撕裂帷幕，迎来的却是愤怒与打压。掩盖源于对“体面”的执念，仿佛真相的曝光便是集体尊严的崩塌。</p> <p>但压制只会换来短暂的平静，深埋的问题终究酿成更大的隐患。家丑如埋藏的火种，与其掩盖，不如直面裂痕，让破碎成为和解与重生的契机。</p> <hr/> <p>Family scandals often linger in silence, hidden beneath layers of secrecy. Each revelation that tears away the veil is met with anger and suppression. This concealment stems from a fixation on preserving “dignity,” as if exposing the truth would spell the collapse of collective honor.</p> <p>Yet, suppression only brings fleeting calm, while buried issues inevitably grow into deeper crises. Scandals are like dormant embers—rather than conceal them, it is better to confront the cracks and turn the rupture into an opportunity for reconciliation and renewal.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>